It's... raining...
Sure is.
But still!
I can't slack off just because it's raining!
I'm going to collect more konpeito!
That was close.
Dobato...!
You got me covered in mud!
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday, your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...The Rain's Gift.
I-It's okay if you get dirty.
The rain will just wash it all off!
No, it's not okay!
I'm all wet now!
Kobato?
Morning.
Miss Sayaka!
Say, Miss Sayaka?
What is it?
Where are we headed?
Your place.
Huh?
We're here.
B-But, it's not a problem if I live here?
If you don't mind, then of course.
Let's take a look inside.
Okay!
Allow me to introduce you.
Her name is Chitose. She's a friend of mine, and works as the landlady here.
N-Nice to meet you!
I'm Kobato Hanato.
Kobato, huh?
Pleasure to meet you. I'm Chitose Mihara.
If you're ever in need of
something, don't hesitate to ask.
I will.
Chitose, mind if I leave the rest to you?
See you later, Kobato.
I have to get back to the nursery.
A-All right!
Thanks for everything!
I'll stop by later to help out.
Looks like Sayaka hasn't changed.
She's always worrying about others.
Kobato.
Yes?
I hope you enjoy your stay.
She looks really nice!
This is where you say, "I'm looking forward to it"!
I-I hope you're looking forward to it!
I'm Kobato Hanato!
You got it the other way around.
Do you know when your luggage will arrive?
U-Umm...
This is all I have!
But what about your bedsheets?
I don't own any!
Oh my.
Well, let me show you around.
Thanks!
This place looks really nice!
Why, thank you.
What a great room, Ioryogi!
Ioryogi?
Huh?
What?
Where did he go?
Dobato...!
How dare you leave me behind...!
I've told you so many times! In this world, I'm nothing but a stuffed animal!!
I'm sorry!
Seriously...
Hey.
Y-Yes?
The nursery opens soon.
I totally forgot!
I have to hurry!
I'm late!
I'm so sorry! Are you all right?!
I'm fine.
But look at your stuffed animal...
Sorry, it's all covered in mud.
How cute!
There!
All clean.
Here.
Bye!
Thank you so much!
She's a lot more considerate than you are.
Kobato.
Do you like your room?
I loved it! There's a roof, and it's really relaxing!
Wow, I'm glad to hear that.
Kobato!
Let's play!
Sorry, but I'm cleaning right now.
Then we'll help you!
Me too!
Thanks!
What do you want me to do?
Let's see...
Hey, what about me?
You didn't have to provide her with an apartment.
But it seems like everyone's excited to have her here.
Don't be mean to her, okay?
How many times...
How many times have you been betrayed like that?
I can see where you're coming from.
You should be cautious of everyone around you.
Good thing it stopped raining.
The nursery's closed tomorrow too.
I'm going to work hard to gather konpeito, Ioryogi!
It was sunny until just a little while ago...
I told you to bring an umbrella!
Sorry...
It doesn't look like it'll stop anytime soon.
I guess we'll just have to walk in it.
Hey, that's not fair! You don't even have to get wet!
Oh, you didn't bring an umbrella?
N-No.
Then here.
Please use it.
But...
It's yours to keep.
It's here for the customers anyway.
Umm...
I'll come return it when it stops raining!
All right.
I'll be waiting.
Okay!
Thank you so much!
You were able to hold a decent conversation.
So, just like that...
Right!
I'll look for people who need to be healed!
I guess you're right in a way.
After all, it's a place that a lot of people visit.
I'll try my best!
No luck...
What is it?
The umbrella's gone!
What?
Perhaps someone took it, thinking it was theirs.
It was probably on purpose.
Huh? Are you allowed to do that?
Of course not!
Oh no...
It was something I borrowed too...
Huh?
You again?
We bumped into each other yesterday!
Something wrong?
Someone took my umbrella...
Here!
You can use mine.
But...
Don't worry about it!
I live right around the corner.
Plus, if you don't have an umbrella, you'll get your stuffed animal wet.
Right?
Mutsumi?
Don't snack too much or you're gonna get fat!
Shut up!
I hate you, Katsuragi!
Get back here!
Hey!
Thanks a lot!
If you don't wait up, I'm going to hit you!
You'll hit me either way!
What did you say?!
Katsuragi!
So there are also people who are willing to give up their umbrella,
even if it means they're going to get wet.
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato.
Oh?
You've got a mark on your face from the floor mat.
H-Have a nice day!
That was so embarrassing!
I can't believe it made a mark on my face!
I bet Miss Chitose thinks I'm a total freak!
Morning!
Huh?
Thanks a lot for the umbrella!
I'm surprised you knew which school I went to.
Well,
when I went to the cake shop to apologize for the umbrella,
he told me that this was the only
school with a green sailor uniform.
Ioryogi was really thankful too.
Ioryogi?
Yup!
Oh, is that the name of your stuffed animal?
Kind of a weird name, don't you think?
I'm Kobato Hanato!
I'm Mutsumi Tadokoro.
Mutsumi.
Your hair's stickin' up in the back.
Shut up!
You're such a pest!
W-Where is it sticking up?
It looks fine.
I've got a mark on my face from sleeping on the floor.
That doesn't exactly make me feel any better...
S-Sorry...
Don't let it get to you!
Well, I've got morning practice. Later!
You know, that boy from earlier is kind of mean.
He reminds me of Kiyokazu.
He'll say mean things to me if I'm late again!
You were a minute and 23 seconds late.
O-One minute?!
Whatever, you're still late.
I-I'm sorry...
You probably slept until the last minute possible, didn't you.
The floor mark already wore off...
I bet you rolled out of your sheets.
I don't own any!
What?
Morning, Kobato.
G-Good morning...
Did Kiyokazu say something mean to you?
Well...
Umm...
He can be a bit blunt, but he's not a bad person.
But if he does bully you, just let me know.
I'll give him a beating.
B-Beating?
Yep, just like in the old days.
Old days...?
Hey! Help me air the sheets for the kids to nap in.
It finally stopped raining.
O-Okay!
I'm coming!
Bye, Kobato!
Bye! See you later!
Looks like we'll be seeing more rain.
Do you carry an umbrella, Kobato?
I don't.
But you do, right, Kiyokazu?
Why don't you walk her home?
I've got something to do after this.
Just take my umbrella.
Besides, I'd hate to have to share an umbrella with you.
Sharing an umbrella...?
It's when couples walk under the same umbrella.
Miss Sayaka was right.
It really started to rain.
The person who took it by
mistake came and put it back.
Huh? Kobato?
I've been seeing you everywhere!
Mutsumi Tadokoro!
Just call me Mutsumi.
So what's up?
I got the umbrella back!
Wow, that's great!
Yeah!
Are you here to shop again?
Yeah.
Fencing practice is really intense and it makes me hungry afterwards.
Looks like you're really into it.
Oh, but...
I'll get fat if I eat too much...
...so you can have this.
Really?
Of course.
Here!
Bye!
They're sharing an umbrella, aren't they?
Mutsumi?!
Mutsumi looked really sad.
I wonder what I could do to cheer her up?
Who knows.
This is going to be a bit difficult...
Good evening!
Please, open the door!
Yes?
A-Are you two all right?!
Yes.
Sorry for the ruckus.
I'm Chiho, the manager's daughter.
I'm Chise.
Pleasure to meet you. I'm Kobato Hanato.
You don't own any bedsheets, right?
Y-Yeah...
Mom told us to bring you this.
Are you sure?
It's a hand-me-down, if you don't mind...
Well then, bye!
Thank you so much!
They gave me sheets!
You're supposed to be the healer, not the one being healed!
Oh... that's right.
I'm going to cheer Mutsumi up.
How?
I... I'll just do whatever I have to do!
Hey! What are you planning?
I think it's better to leave her be for now.
Hey!
Huh?
I-I need to talk to you for a second.
About Mutsumi.
Please!
Huh...? What do you mean?
I'm saying...
I want you to share an
umbrella with Mutsumi too!
Please!
What do you mean, "with Mutsumi too"?!
Is it not possible?
Mutsumi!
What's going on?
It's just that... you looked really sad the other day...
Huh?
When you were sharing an
umbrella with another girl...
N-No, I wasn't really...!
Then why did you look so...?
That's...
That's because...
I apologize if I'm just meddling.
I just wanted you to cheer up...
So...
Here!
Please share an umbrella with Mutsumi!
Kobato?!
Please!
I'd feel bad for the girl from the other day.
Sure.
S-Shut up! I said I don't care!
I'm not dating that girl or anything.
Huh?
She... forgot her umbrella, so I was just walking her home.
Mutsumi.
Come on.
Hurry up.
Let's go!
Ralph!!
Wait up!
You're going to get me soaked!
Give me some more room.
Quit complaining.
It's so packed in here!
Geez...
I'm just stating the truth.
I can't help it. It's a small umbrella.
Mutsumi doesn't look too happy.
It's fine.
Really?
This is strange, Ioryogi.
What's strange?
There's more in the jar.
Didn't you heal her to collect konpeito?
I just wanted her to cheer up...
Either way, you were able to heal her broken heart.
Really?
The proof is right there in the jar.
Then I'm happy!
I fear for the future...
I just felt something...
What's the matter, Kohaku?
No, it's nothing, Shuichiro.
Let's go.
You did pretty well this time, so I guess it wouldn't hurt to give you a good grade.
Really?!
A-Are you all right, Ioryogi?!
Do...ba...to...!
You get a zero!
That's so mean, Ioryogi!
You just said you'd give me a good grade!
I'm always getting splashed with mud and ink and whatever because of you!
I-It'll be okay!
The rain will wash it all off!
The rain can't wash away my anger!
No way!
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...When the Green Leaves Flourish.